<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Job Hunting? on Michael Aguilar</title>
    <link>/job-hunting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Job Hunting? on Michael Aguilar</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 14:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/job-hunting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About the Job Hunt</title>
      <link>/job-hunting/about-the-job-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/job-hunting/about-the-job-hunt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right now, the job market is really difficult. It&amp;rsquo;s tough for everyone working white-collar jobs, but it&amp;rsquo;s especially bad for new grads, or those with limited experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a very frustrating experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s clarify who is actually making the hiring decision and why you may not make it past each stage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiring Managers</title>
      <link>/job-hunting/the-hiring-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/job-hunting/the-hiring-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It all starts with the hiring manager. They have an opening, and they need to find some candidates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hiring manager will create a job description, and send it to a recruiter. In a larger organization, HR will play a big part in this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re also very involved at the end. They have the final say as to whether or not a candidate is selected. Don&amp;rsquo;t blame the recruiter - they didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything to do with it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem with hiring managers:&lt;/strong&gt; Most managers don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about hiring people. For many, it&amp;rsquo;s something they do once or twice a year, if that often.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recruiters</title>
      <link>/job-hunting/recruiters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/job-hunting/recruiters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recruiter will take the job description and post it somewhere. They may do it themselves, and/or send it to one or more third-party agencies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that recruiters are paid to place people into jobs. If they don&amp;rsquo;t find someone, they don&amp;rsquo;t get paid.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They have a lot of incentive to find someone &lt;em&gt;the hiring manager will accept&lt;/em&gt;. Not necessarily the best candidate, but the one that will get them paid the most money for the least effort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem with recruiters:&lt;/strong&gt; They&amp;rsquo;re all different. They all have their own way of evaluating candidates. Ask three recruiters what&amp;rsquo;s the best way to get a job, and you&amp;rsquo;ll get five answers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Generated Resumes</title>
      <link>/job-hunting/ai-generated-resumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 13:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/job-hunting/ai-generated-resumes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you apply on LinkedIn, you may see that a given job has &amp;ldquo;100+&amp;rdquo; applicants in less than a day. That&amp;rsquo;s not a mistake, or a typo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just because you see so many applicants doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t apply if you&amp;rsquo;re qualified. You should.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adding to the difficulty is that many of those 100+ applicants are faking it. It isn&amp;rsquo;t difficult to create a resume based on the job description. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to apply, so plenty of unqualified people just go for it. The potential  of getting a job is a huge reward for very little effort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem with AI Generated resumes:&lt;/strong&gt; With the popularization of AI, creating and submitting a tailored resume is easier than ever. It will be perfectly formatted, have relevant bullet points, and follow the STAR method.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Automatic Tracking System</title>
      <link>/job-hunting/the-automatic-tracking-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 13:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/job-hunting/the-automatic-tracking-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An applicant will submit their resume, and it will be parsed - with varying results - into an Automatic Tracking System. Job descriptions, dates, and keywords will be added to various fields in a database.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recruiters seldom read every resume that comes in. Some still do, but given how many applications they receive it&amp;rsquo;s become even less common.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem with the ATS:&lt;/strong&gt; When a recruiter queries the ATS, they look for keywords, and get back a list of applications with a score. If an applicant&amp;rsquo;s keywords don&amp;rsquo;t line up, then they get a lower score. They won&amp;rsquo;t be rejected. They won&amp;rsquo;t even be considered.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Team Interview</title>
      <link>/job-hunting/the-team-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 13:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/job-hunting/the-team-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One or more interviews will be with your future co-workers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These interviews have a lot of impact on whether or not you&amp;rsquo;ll be hired. They aren&amp;rsquo;t always make-or-break, but the hiring manager will take their feedback very seriously.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The questions are usually technical in nature: &amp;ldquo;describe what a load balancer does&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;what does it mean when you get this error?&amp;rdquo;, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You may even get a curveball, like &amp;ldquo;tell me about a time you had to give bad news to your boss&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
