<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Job Hunting on Michael Aguilar</title>
    <link>https://michael-aguilar.com/job-hunting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Job Hunting on Michael Aguilar</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 14:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://michael-aguilar.com/job-hunting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Job Hunting and Recruiters</title>
      <link>https://michael-aguilar.com/job-hunting/job-hunting-and-recruiters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://michael-aguilar.com/job-hunting/job-hunting-and-recruiters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recruiter will take the job description and post it somewhere. They may do it themselves, and/or send it to one or more third-party agencies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that recruiters are paid to place people into jobs. If they don&amp;rsquo;t find someone, they don&amp;rsquo;t get paid.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They have a lot of incentive to find someone &lt;em&gt;the hiring manager will accept&lt;/em&gt;. Not necessarily the best candidate, but the one that will get them paid the most money for the least effort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem with recruiters:&lt;/strong&gt; They&amp;rsquo;re all different. They all have their own way of evaluating candidates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Job Hunting and AI Generated Resumes</title>
      <link>https://michael-aguilar.com/job-hunting/job-hunting-and-ai-generated-resumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 13:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://michael-aguilar.com/job-hunting/job-hunting-and-ai-generated-resumes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you apply on LinkedIn, you may see that a given job has &amp;ldquo;100+&amp;rdquo; applicants in less than a day. That&amp;rsquo;s not a mistake, or a typo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the popularization of AI, creating and submitting a tailored resume is easier than ever. It will be perfectly formatted, have relevant bullet points, and follow the STAR method. There are web sites out there which will do the work for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adding to the difficulty is that many of those 100+ applicants are faking it. It isn&amp;rsquo;t difficult to create a resume based on the job description. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to apply, so plenty of unqualified people just go for it. The potential  of getting a job is a huge reward for very little effort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just because you see so many applicants doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t apply if you&amp;rsquo;re qualified. You should.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Job Hunting and the Automatic Tracking System</title>
      <link>https://michael-aguilar.com/job-hunting/job-hunting-and-the-automatic-tracking-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 13:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://michael-aguilar.com/job-hunting/job-hunting-and-the-automatic-tracking-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An applicant will submit their resume, and it will be parsed - with varying results - into an Automatic Tracking System. Job descriptions, dates, and keywords will be added to various fields in a database.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recruiters seldom read every resume that comes in. Some still do, but given how many applications they receive it&amp;rsquo;s become even less common.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem with the ATS:&lt;/strong&gt; They&amp;rsquo;re primitive, at best. AI is becoming more common, but it tends to be naive. When a recruiter queries the ATS, they look for keywords, and get back a list of applications with a score. If an applicant&amp;rsquo;s keywords don&amp;rsquo;t line up, then they get a lower score. They won&amp;rsquo;t be rejected. They won&amp;rsquo;t even be considered.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
